### Contact

muhammadasifhaqnawaz2019@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ muhammadasif2021 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

JavaScript

React.js

Node.js

### Languages

Saraiki (Native or Bilingual)
Punjabi (Limited Working)
English (Professional Working)
Urdu (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

You Need a Career Development Plan

Learning REST APIs
Mel Robbins on Confidence
Finding a Job on LinkedIn
Git and Github

Honors-Awards

PM Laptop Scheme Holder

# Muhammad Asif

Full-Stack Software Engineer (ReactJS/ExpressJS/NodeJS/MongoDB) | @React Enthusiast

Lahore District

# Summary

Goal: To become a Prominent Software Engineer and lead the product development team in a multinational tech company.

Confidence to communicate and works in team projects with belief in continuous growth.

Present: Currently, focused on Coding ReactJS and NodeJS backend applications and dreaming of ReactJS Expert. Help companies build complex web applications serving customers with React and modern technologies. Working in a tech company focused on eCommerce-based services.

Skills: React, Redux, JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB (many more)

Belonged from a humble background, feel the honor and pride of holding the degree of University of Engineering and Technology Lahore. The four-year journey was some precious time of my life that completely changed my view. I sensed the difference created during the period.

# Experience

### Qbatch

Associate Software Engineer July 2021 - Present (9 months) Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Full-Stack Developer: Understand the client requirements and build the features using the MERN technology stack.

• Backend Development (RESTFUL API): Working on building the applications using the rest-backed APIs e.g., Stripe API, Agenda, MWS API. Setting up the connection and schema for MongoDB database and interacting with the API calls.

• Front End Development: Developing the react component, managing the states using Redux Toolkit, and interacting with the backend through middleware's (Axios, thunk)

#### Omdena

Junior Machine Learning Engineer July 2021 - August 2021 (2 months)

Selected as one of the 50 contributors to work on the project titled "Helping the Energy Industry Achieve Digital Transformation Through AI"

Amal Academy
Amal Career-Prep Fellowship
December 2020 - February 2021 (3 months)
Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Education startup funded by Stanford University that teaches professional skills to students and corporations

- Communication: Completed a competitive written application and interview process to be selected from over 4900 applicants for an intensive 3-month
   Fellowship funded by Stanford University
- Skills development: Investing 150 hours in order to develop business skills (e.g., communication,

leadership, problem-solving, teamwork, etc.) that will help me make a deeper impact on the job

Commitment: Completed 15 online courses, 6 projects, and working on 1 mega project

#### **KICS**

Wordpress Developer December 2020 - January 2021 (2 months) Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Researcher: Evaluated 50 startup website to understand the norm and selected one best theme for the website

Developer: Customized Incubator theme and pages to match the requirements

### Education

University of Engineering and Technology, Lahore Bachelor's degree, Computer Science (2017 - 2021)

Superior College

Intermediate, Pre-Engineering · (2015 - 2017)